Guide to the Reynolds Student Investment Fund Records, 1952-1968
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Reynolds Student Investment Fund records 1952-1968
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. Dept. of Economics. Reynolds Student Investment Fund.
1.0 Linear Feet approximately 1000 Items
The Reynolds Student Investment Fund began in 1952 in conjunction with Professor Frederic Joerg's Investments course in the Duke University Department of Economics and Business Administration as a means to introduce students to investment practices.
The collection includes financial reports, trust agreements, analyses, and related materials from the years 1952 to 1968.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Reynolds Student Investment Fund Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1973.
Historical Note
The Reynolds Student Investment Fund began in 1952 as an extra project associated with the Investments course in Duke's Department of Economics and Business Administration taught by Frederic Joerg. The fund began with $10,000, donated by Charles H. Babcock of Winston-Salem. Fidelity Bank of Durham acted as the Trustee and the Student Governing Board requested that it purchase stocks, bonds and/or securities. Students in the Investments course purchased and analyzed stocks on behalf of the fund and donated all proceeds to the Durham Community Chest. The investment decisions were voted on by a quorum.
Collection Overview
Collection includes trust agreements, orders, appraisals, bank statements, financial reports, student orders to buy and sell, financial analyses, audit materials and brokerage firm reports from the years roughly 1952 to 1968.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Dept. of Economics. Reynolds Student Investment Fund.
Duke University -- History -- 20th century.
Duke University. Students -- Vocational guidance.
Joerg, Frederick Charles.
Related Material
News Service Biographical Files, 1960-2004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library/University Archives, Duke University
Biographical Reference Collection, 1972-2004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library/University Archives, Duke University
Dept. of Economics Records
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library/University Archives, Duke University
Frederick Joerg Papers
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library/University Archives, Duke University
Craufurd D. W. Goodwin Papers, 1963-1994
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library/University Archives, Duke University
Benjamin U. Ratchford Papers, 1924-1980
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library/University Archives, Duke University
Calvin B. Hoover Papers, 1929-1988 (bulk 1929-1968)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library/University Archives, Duke University
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Trust Agreement, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Orders and Appraisals, 1960-1962
  - Bank Statements, Trust Agreement, Market Appraisals and Letters, 1964-1966
  - Reports, 1966-1968
  - Reports, 1957-1960
  - Orders and Reports, 1957-1960
  - Student Orders to Buy and Sell, 1952-1955
  - Progress Reports, 1960-1961
  - Final Report, 1956-1957
  - Summary Report, 1958
  - Bank Reports, 1957-1959
  - Orders and Reports, 1953-1955
  - Bank Reports, 1952-1967 (Box 2)
  - Audits, 1952-1962
  - Statements and Audit Papers, 1960
  - Analysis of Dow Chemical Company, 1963
  - Student Papers, 1963
  - Brokerage Firm Reports, 1965-1966
  - Proposals and Income Statements, 1952-1959